MIYAKO JONES

Software Engineer

mtj@miyako.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/miyakoj https://www.miyako.io

PROFILE

4 years of combined experience with website development and software engineering. Organized, responsible, hardworking, a team player and a self-starter. Skills include:

• Client-side development.

Server-side development.

• Object-oriented development.

Design, testing, debugging, and documentation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C#, .NET Framework, .NET Core, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, C++, Java, Python

Libraries: jQuery, Fabric

Frameworks: Bootstrap 3 & 4, Daemonite's Material UI, Angular 1, Vue.is 2

Platforms: Node.js, Electron

Methodologies: UML, Agile, Google's Material Design

OS: Windows, Linux

Databases: MySQL, SQL Server, SQLite, MongoDB, Firebase

Software: Visual Studio/Code, Git, Subversion, WordPress, Oracle SQL Developer, SharePoint, Visio

Cloud: Digital Ocean, Azure, Jira, Stripe, Recurly, Google Cloud

WORK HISTORY

SWIFTLET TECHNOLOGY, Flint, MI (2017 to Present)

Contract Software Engineer (Nov. 2020 to Present)

Designed, developed, debugged, estimated, and maintained web, server, and desktop software.

Software Engineer (Mar. 2017 to Oct. 2020)

Designed, developed, debugged, estimated, and maintained web, server, and desktop software.

- Added functionality to existing websites using ASP.NET.
- Updated existing web application data integrations and databases using Entity Framework and SQL Server.
- Developed tools using .NET, Node.js, and Groovy to interface with Jira in order to achieve business goals.
- Developed an Odoo POS addon in JavaScript.
- Developed an Electron-based application to work with SMART cryptocurrency wallets and a supporting JSON-RPC tool. (SmartSweeper | node-smartcash)
- Ported an existing .NET Framework application to .NET Core.
- Developed .NET UI applications using Winforms.
- Utilized the Selenium Framework for web application testing.
- Developed web and desktop applications to display simultaneous video streams.

- Developed dashboard web application with Stripe integration using Angular 1 and PHP.
- Developed and maintained WordPress sites.

Contract Software Engineer (Jan. 2017 to Mar. 2017)

Developed a web-based tool for YMCA youth to track environmental impact using Angular 1.

UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN-FLINT, Flint, MI (2007 to 2016)

Lead Web Developer, Dept. of Computer Science (May 2016 to Dec. 2016)

Developed web-based tools using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery, Bootstrap, and PHP to assist Flint residents and city officials with navigating the Flint Water Crisis. (Project repo)

- Worked with Google UX designers to develop a responsive, user-friendly website.
- Leading role in designing and developing backend logic to connect web tools to Google Cloud products such as Cloud Storage and Cloud SQL.
- Led a team of 4 developers in client-side and server-side development.
- Developed and released open source software.

Office Assistant/Webmaster, Honors Program (Jan. 2013 to Jun. 2016)

Assisted program staff with the administration of the Honors Program.

- Developed and maintained a SharePoint website and workflow processes for Honors off-campus applications.
- Developed and maintained a SharePoint site for Honors theses.
- Developed and edited content for the Honors Program website using Drupal.
- Communicated professionally with faculty, staff, students, and alumni.
- Assisted with the revision of business processes.
- Distributed information at student orientation sessions and assisted with student recruitment.
- Wrote and edited articles for the Honors Discovery newsletter and Honors blog.

Graduate Student Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science (Mar. 2016 to Apr. 2016)

Assisted with the research and development of software products.

- Developed an editor using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript/jQuery for updating the Firebase database used for the h2oFlint Android app. (Post)
- Researched solutions for a virtual lab system that integrated audio and video communications technology.

Desktop Publisher/Web Developer/Research Assistant, Office of Research (Feb. 2009 to Dec. 2012)

Assisted with the creation and maintenance of the Linden Legal Aid Centre website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.

- Designed the newsletter of the Linden Legal Aid Centre.
- Assisted with information research for the Linden Legal Aid Centre website and newsletter.
- Established variables and entered data using IBM SPSS software.

UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN-FLINT (Continued)

Office Assistant/Webmaster, Dept. of Philosophy (May 2008 to Apr. 2009)

Assisted faculty and staff with the administration of the department.

- Answered telephone calls using a multi-line system.
- Answered questions from staff and students.
- Maintained department website.
- Digitized course materials.

Website Developer/Webmaster, Various Departments (Aug. 2007 to Apr. 2009)

Created and maintained the websites of several academic departments and programs using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

- Designed and developed informational pop-ups for department courses.
- Created instructor web pages.
- Updated information and maintained its accuracy.
- Utilized a content management system to maintain web pages.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan-Flint, Flint, MI

- Master of Science, Computer Science and Information Systems
- Software outreach student
- 3.7/4.0 GPA
- Graduation date: Apr. 29, 2016

University of Michigan-Flint, Flint, MI

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Software Engineering (Honors)
- Minor: Computer Information Systems
- 2012 Maize and Blue Scholar | 2009 Google Scholar
- 3.61/4.0 GPA
- Graduation date: Dec. 19, 2012

VOLUNTEER

Software Developer, University of Michigan-Flint (Sep. 2009 to Jun. 2012)

Worked with a team to develop a transcultural nursing educational game for undergraduates.

- Created UML-based software artifacts such as use cases and sequence diagrams.
- Wrote a software requirements specification for a software component.
- Constructed companion software for the nursing game using Java.
- Created PHP scripts to transfer data from a Flash application to a remote MySQL database.

Software Developer, University of Michigan-Flint (May 2010 to Aug. 2010)

Worked with a team to design a biology/chemistry educational game for undergraduates using UML.

Successfully reused a framework previously developed for a similar educational game.

References

Laura Staudacher

Daniel Kurin Swiftlet Technology LLC Founder and CEO

 $\underline{dkurin@swiftlet.technology}$ Flint, MI **Current Supervisor**

989-225-8754

Mark Allison Associate Chair and Assistant Professor

Department of Computer Science University of Michigan-Flint markalli@umich.edu

810-762-3131 Former Supervisor Program Manager Honors Program

laurast@umich.edu University of Michigan-Flint

Former Supervisor 810-424-5354